http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly
(INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN: (ON RADIO) ...with some lingering
clouds around Kodiak Island.
Look for a chance of
overnight showers
along the mountainous areas
of South Eastern Alaska.
And now back to music on
KBWZ, Alaska listens.
RICKY: Brad?
Wait, you cut out. What?
(COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING ON RADIO)
No, dude, my parents
went to Europe
and they sent us to Alaska
to hang outwith my uncle.
It's fine.
Yeah, my uncle is
a paleontologist.
He collects dinosaur bones. I guess
he's taking us to work with him.
Brad?
Brad? Brad, are you there?
Great, no signal.
Where are we going anyway?
I'll give you a clue.
I got it in here somewhere.
Ah, there we go!
Check it out.
What is it?
That, my friend, is the
tooth of a Gorgosaurus.
- Cool!
- Isn't it?
You know, it was almost as big
as a T-Rex, but way faster.
They roamed the Earth millions of
years ago and they got wiped out.
Their only living descendants
are birds and blah, blah, blah.
Oh, come on, man. You used to love
dinosaurs, you were an expert.
This guy must have
been really scary.
How do you think
he lost his tooth?
- The Gorge?
- Yeah.
I wonder if he was in, like, a huge
fight with a load of other dinosaurs.
My friend, Natalie, she ran into a
flagpole at school and lost two teeth.
There was blood everywhere.
Yeah, a flagpole will do that.
Let's go!
You sure you don't
want to come?
I'm not really into
digging up dead things.
All right. Well, stay
close to the truck.
If you change your mind
just follow the trail up.
Got it.
Okay, bud.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
MALE VOICE: Psst!
(BIRD CAWING)
MALE VOICE: Psst! Psst!
Hey, kid.
Yeah, you. I'm talking to you.
What's wrong? You never
heard a bird talk before?
You think you're pretty
smart, don't you?
It's all right. I'm
not offended about
those things you said
about my ancestors.
Totally cool with it. You
should see your ancestors.
Three words: U-g-ly.
(CHUCKLES)
But you know that every
fossil tells a story...
and this tooth tells
a pretty good one.
So go ahead and pick it up.
Come on, come on, pick it up.
Pick it up, pick it up!
Come on, it won't bite you.
Not anymore, at least.
(CHUCKLES)
it will, however, open a
window into the ancient past.
A vibrant world of
wonder and danger,
when dinosaurs
roamed the earth...
and birds looked a
little more like this.
There, you see? Now we can begin.
(CHUCKLES)
And try to keep up, will you?!
ALEX: 70 million years ago, in the late
Cretaceous period of planet Earth...
there lived a miraculous...
bird. That's me, Alex!
BOY: Alexornis, meaning
Alexander's Bird, insectivore.
ALEX: Note the
beautiful plumage...
majestic wingspan, the
classically curved beak.
Not to brag, but I am kind
of the whole package.
Of course, if you're familiar
with the Cretaceous Period,
you probably know all of this.
Hmm.
Now watch closely.
This is a delicate operation,
best left to the professionals.
Ah, the enticing
smell of decay.
Look at this tartar build-up.
Mmm!
Hey, watch it!
(GROWLS)
I'm telling you, it's
hard out here for a bird!
But enough about me.
The story you're about to see
concerns a friend of mine.
I gotta say, it's a
pretty good one,
filled with mystery
and adventure...
hope and despair.
Excuse me while I take a
personal moment. Gotcha!
By the way, this isn't the guy I was
talking about. It's his mother.
She is a Pachyrhinosaurus.
GIRL: Pachyrhinosaurus, meaning
thick-nosed lizard, herbivore.
ALEX: But pay attention, because the
adventures of her son, Patchi...
are the stuff of legend.
Which has nothing to do with
that stuff right there.
Let me at it. Hey,
that's not fair!
ALEX: There he is!
That's Patchi.
Mm-mm, barf.
ALEX: The runt of
the litter, the guy
at the bottom of
the pecking order.
- ALEX: Hey, Patchi!
- Can't talk now, Alex!
Trying to work on my
survival instincts!
Excuse me, Alpha
male coming through.
Pardon, I'm just
gonna have a bite.
Back off, Patchi.
What about my fair share?
Your fair share was delicious.
That's my big brother, Scowler.
He's usually really cool.
He just gets weird around puke.
Mm, there's some of it now.
Sometimes you gotta
think outside the nest.
So now I just gotta
get out of the nest.
BOY: Troodon, meaning
wounding tooth, omnivore.
Alex might say I'm a runt, but
you gotta start somewhere.
From zero to hero, baby.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on. I'm
the one telling the story!
I have more credibility here.
It's my story, Alex.
Yeah, but I have a more
neutral perspective.
Wait a minute. Are you
really gonna eat that?
You know it. Mom's
cooking, and still warm!
- Uh-oh! Run away!
- Where you going?
All right, more for me.
ALEX: Seriously, there's a
big monster behind you!
Sure, there's a big monster
behind you too! (CHUCKLES)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
ALEX: So much for your
survival instincts!
Help!
(ROARS)
PATCHI: Okay, so I
quickly learned that
not everybody eats
puked-up leaves.
There are things out
here called meat-eaters.
ALEX: Exactly, and you, my friend,
are made up almost entirely of meat.
Hey, put me down!
Lam not a chew toy!
(ROARING)
PATCHY. Good thing
my dad showed up.
ALEX: That's Bulldust,
Patchi's 6, 000-pound papa.
PATCHI: Nobody
messes with him.
Hey, Dad, little help?
Oh! Whoa! Whoa!
Thank you!
(GROANS)
Medic!
PATCHI: Classic Dad. He
was a man of few words.
ALEX: Actually, he was
a man of one word.
(ROARING LOUDLY)
That one.
Huh? What is that?
ALEX: That, my friend,
is a hole in your head.
But don't worry, one day that hole
will be filled with greatness.
PATCHI: Right! Plus you
can hardly see it.
ALEX: Especially if you don't
look at it. Besides...
mistakes are natural
at a young age.
Look at that!
Leaving the nest was
totally worth it!
Hey, what's going on up there?
(FLATULENCE)
(EXCLAIMING)
What is this?
ALEX: That is the price
of leaving the nest.
Oh, who are you?
You're pretty cool.
Come over here!
Where you going?
Hey, don't be afraid.
I'm not gonna eat
you or anything.
He will.
(GASPS)
(SNIFFING)
Hey, there. Name's Patchi.
Wanna be friends?
Wait, wait! Wait up!
I don't always
smell like this!
I'm just covered in
poop at the moment!
Aw, come on! Are we playing tag?
Is that what this is?
Okay, I guess I'm
it then, right?
(GROWLING)
Whoa.
GIRL: Ankylosaur, meaning
fused lizard, herbivore.
This thing is huge!
Which means I should probably
steer clear of his butt.
ALEX: Good for you, Patchi.
You're learning.
(SNEEZES)
Wow! This is the most beautiful
place I've ever seen.
ALEX: It's a future oil field,
so don't get too attached.
Hey! Pick on someone
your own size!
Uh, you know, I mean, if that's
a convenient option for you.
Oop, there he goes.
You lost him.
BOY: Hesperonychus, meaning
Western claw, carnivore.
No, I didn't mean me!
Oh, you misunderstood!
I meant my brother!
Yeah, he's bigger,
he's meatier.
He's a lot slower! Oh,
he's so tender... Oh!
Hey, Ma. Oh, I had it, but
thanks for showing up.
(GROWLS)
ALEX: And so, with a
little help from Mom...
Patchi returned from his first
adventure a little bit wiser...
and a whole lot smellier.
Hey. Guys. You are not gonna
believe what just happened to me.
Oh, my gosh! Did you just
take a poop shower?!
No.
Maybe.
Define poop shower.
ALEX: They were all jealous, Patchi,
'cause you'd been out in the world.
You were on your way
to becoming a grownup.
♪  One day I fell in love and ♪
♪  You took all of my heart ♪
♪  Twenty four hours, ♪
♪ blue sky, sun rays ♪
♪  Where there used to be grey ♪
I Used to be grey
♪  Say goodbye to ♪
♪ yesterday Oh, oh ♪
♪  What a difference ♪
♪ today made I ♪
Right, Dad, got it!
Knock down the tree
and feast on the leafy
Greens up top! Mmm-mmm.
Yeah, I also got it, Dad. I'm
just gonna square up here and...
knock down the tree!
I'll square up and
knock down the tree.
Oh, I'm gonna just gonna grab...
He's stronger than he looks.
Gonna feast on that leafy...
- Okay.
- SCOWLER: Uh, Dad?
Are we really from
the same litter?
ALEX: Okay, what's so special
about dust? I don't get it.
You roll around on your back and
you make some grunting noises.
- I mean, how is that a hobby?
- PATCHY. What?
Oh, man! You haven't
lived until
you've taken a dirt bath.
It's the best.
Here, let me get
in there, fellas.
Yeah, oh, boy!
It's so fun.
You gotta try... (YELLS)
Hey, hey, hey!
Watch the plumage!
- How would you like it if I did this?
- Ow!
- Hey, watch the nose!
- You watch it!
- No, you watch it!
GIRL: Alphadon, meaning
first tooth, omnivore.
Patch! Pachito, come
on, wait for me!
I'm sorry I went all pre-historic
on you back there, okay, buddy?
It's okay, Alex.
PATCHI: What's going on?
ALEX: Major is challenging your
father for the role of leader!
It's a time honored tradition.
Oh, yeah, and Major's toast!
Dad's gonna crush him!
Come on, Dad! Show
him who's boss!
Introduce your
horn to his head!
- Yeah, smack.
- Ah! Quit it!
Hey. Dad!
Wow, Dad, that was awesome!
You kicked his butt all the
way up to the Stone age.
Get back here!
PATCHI: I may have been
smaller than my brother.
ALEX: But you made up
for it by running away.
PATCHI: No, no, no. I
wasn't running away.
I was racing him...
and winning.
- Are you ready?!
- Yeah.
Are you sure? I'm pretty sure.
Are you ready?! H it me!
All right!
- I wasn't ready.
- Yeah.
- I'm ready now.
- Be quiet.
Come back, you
coward, both of you!
We're good.
I want some more. You want some more!
Everybody wants more and more?
SCOWLER: Did you guys see that?
Totally rang his bell.
ALEX: And so the
young Pachyrhinosaur
frolicked and fritted
away his youth.
Why? I dunno. The kid
likes to frolic.
But all that was
about to change.
PATCHI: And it all started
the day I met... Juniper.
(FUNKY MUSIC PLAYING)
♪  Oh, baby ♪
♪  Give it up ♪
♪  Ain't no use I ♪
Hi, I'm Patchi.
I'm made of meat.
That's not what
I meant to say.
I meant to say, "I'm Patchi."
Whoa, is that a
hole in your head?
Uh, no. I mean...
yeah, technically...
I like it.
Ah, young love, so beautiful,
so precious. Gotcha!
Really, I've never seen anything
like that before. (ROARS)
- Really?
- There's my mom.
I'm sorry, I have to go.
Ah, but we just met!
I'm not supposed to talk
to guys outside my herd.
Stupid rules.
I'm sorry. Goodbye.
Wait, wait, don't go!
Just stay for one minute!
Ah, no!
Sniff me out later, okay?
Oh.
(WHOOPING)
Yeah! She likes me!
And she likes my hole.
ALEX: Over the next few days,
Patchi returned to the waterfall...
for he had been bitten by the love
bug, the tastiest bug of all.
But the lady proved
to be elusive.
Not to be denied,
the young lover
pursued his passion
nonetheless...
once more returning to the
sight of his glorious vision.
And he just kept
coming back...
really to the point of overkill,
if you want my opinion.
Ah, man. Where is she?
Oh, didn't I tell you?
She moved South.
South? When?
Four or five days ago.
How long have you known this?
About four or five days.
Gotcha!
(SIGHS)
ALEX: But Juniper and
her family were headed.
South as part of the
great migration...
for the summer was coming to an
end and food was in short supply.
Especially the bug supply, which
is very, very important to me.
More than anything, Patchi
wanted to follow Juniper...
and his impatience was
beginning to show.
The birds are going South. Those
green things are going South.
When do we get to go South?
ALEX: It'll be time to go when
your father says it's time.
(ROARING)
ALEX: It's time.
Move 'em out, Patchi.
You don't have to
tell me twice.
Move 'em out, Patchi.
Right, here we go.
My first migration.
(ROARS)
SCOWLER: Eat my dust, Patchi.
PATCHI: It's not a race.
ALEX: Come on, guys,
don't be shy.
We're all going to
the same place.
Hey, Alex, don't most
birds fly South?
It's called symbiosis, buddy. I get
transportation and you get pest control.
Gotcha!
Seriously, you're a
buffet on four legs.
And the herd lumbered South
across the Alaskan hinterland...
PATCH: Whoa, what do
you mean, lumbered?
ALEX: Well, you weren't
exactly gallivanting.
PATCHI: Yeah, we're Pachyrhinosaurs.
We don't gallivant.
ALEX: No, you do not,
but I have to warn you,
every good story
has a scary part
and that's coming
up, so get ready.
PATCHI: Oh, I'm ready.
I lived through it.
It was late afternoon and the
clouds were gathering in the east.
ALEX: Okay, okay, let me
tell it. I have the flair.
The clouds gathered
in the east.
Soon, a portent of
approaching danger
floated in upon the
changing winds...
a harbinger in the form of a
glorious winged creature.
ALEX: Danger, danger, everyone!
Warning, warning!
Did you hear that, Dad?
Danger.
SCOWLER: Of course he heard.
(ROARS)
What'd I say, huh?
PATCHI: My father ordered
the herd into the Forest
to find shelter
from the storm.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
ALEX: The weather worsened, and
my friend Patchi's young life...
was about to change in a ﬂash.
I'm scared. (GASPS)
I'm not scared. You're the
only one who's scared.
(SCREECHES)
Well, you and maybe that guy.
Wusses.
ALEX: The dry summer months had
turned the Forest into a tinderbox...
ready to explode into flames.
I know you humans like to
think you discovered fire...
but trust me, it's been around
since the time of
the dinosaurs.
Patchi's father
smelled trouble.
Quickly, he called to the others.
(ROARS)
This was no time
to dilly-dally.
Dad, what's going on?
- What is it, Alex'?
- It's fire!
What's fire? Does
it eat meat?!
It eats everything. Run!
Go on! Move your
meaty little legs!
ALEX: Bulldust and his family
hurried toward open ground.
But there was
just one problem:
Predators.
For one dinosaur's misfortune
is another dinosaur's feast.
Hi there! Friend or foe?
Foe, foe, definitely foe!
Wait up, guys!
Scowler, I don't like migration!
I wanna go home!
Patchi, try and be
brave like Dad.
What do we do now?
What do we do?!
Don't worry, Dad would
never abandon me.
You mean us, right?
Right, us.
PATCHI: Help, Dad!
SCOWLER: Dad, over here!
That was a good idea, Dad.
I was gonna do the same thing,
bust through that tree.
PATCHI: Hey, where's Mom?
ALEX: Separated
from the others...
Patchi's mom didn't realize that
she was heading into a trap.
(SNARLING)
She did what she
could to protect her
little ones, but the
danger only mounted.
Severely outnumbered, she called
for Bulldust to come and help.
(ROARS)
PATCHI: We should go with him.
Patchi, Dad said to wait here!
I don't care. Dad!
Let me do it. I'm louder. Dad!
Wait a minute, Scowler,
I think I see him!
Dad!
He's coming back!
That's definitely... not him.
Oh, boy, oh, boy,
run, run, run!
We should split up. He'll
only eat one of us.
The slower one, right?
On second thought, we
better stick together!
Over here, under those logs!
I think we lost him. The smoke
is disguising our scent.
PATCHI: Really? You think?
His tongue touched me! I was
literally on the tip of his tongue!
Dad!
I knew he'd come back for me!
For us! You mean, us!
Right, I said us.
Get him, Dad! Stomp his butt!
Yeah, get him, Dad!
Do you think he'll win?
What are you talking about?!
Dad always wins.
Always. Right? I
mean, he's got to.
ALEX: But this time, Bulldust,
the great Pachyrhinosaur...
the most feared and
respected of his tribe...
had met his match.
On that day, noble
blood was spilled...
while noble blood looked on.
It's gonna be okay.
It's gonna be okay,
it's gonna be okay.
SCOWLER: Anyone out there?
PATCHI: Can anyone hear us?
Hello?
Mom?
Dad?
Scowler, you see anything?
Hello, anyone out there?
Hello? Mom!
- Patchi.
- Dad!
Patchi, come on, we've
gotta keep moving.
PATCHI: But what
if they come back?
I don't know. They'll find us.
Gotta get to the herd, okay?
Yeah, but Scowler,
I'm just saying,
what's the harm in
waiting a little?
I'm sure they'd do
the same for us.
They're not coming back, okay?
Hello, Mom?
I'm not giving up. Dad! Dad?!
Aw, poor kid. I
wish I could help.
Hey, somebody's coming!
Dad?
It's Major! Major!
PATCHI: Major, it's us!
SCOWLER: Major!
PATCHI: Oh, Major, I'm
so happy to see you!
It was crazy! There was
this fire, then these mean
psycho Gorges came
out of nowhere.
But Dad fought them off
and now he's gone...
- Oh, okay.
- Geez.
Good talk.
Huh. He seemed kind of busy.
I guess he's leader
of the herd now.
Come on, follow me!
Um, if he's the leader of the
herd, why am I following you?
SCOWLER: 'Cause I'm still
the leader of you! Come on!
All right. I'm coming.
We've got to stick together. It's
just you and me now, all right?
Pay attention, and
watch your back.
Yeah, I got it. Ooh!
Sorry, ladies.
Sweet pond scum, it's her!
She looks amazing.
Hey! Hey. Over here! Juniper!
It's me! Uh, the guy with
the hole in his head?
Hey, Patchi, you
migrating with us now?
PATCHI: I've been looking
all over for you.
I went back to the
waterfall so many times.
But it was weird, it was
like you just disappear...
Aw, come on!
Oh, I see, playing hard to get.
Nice.
I feel ya.
Hey, Juniper, wait up!
Wait for me!
What're you doing?
Who you talking to?
Um, a friend.
A friend? Since when
do you have friends?
PATCHI: I have
tons of friends.
Wait. Hold on! It's a girl, isn't it?!
(CHUCKLES)
PATCHI: What?
Patchi's got a girlfriend.
She's not my girlfriend.
ALEX: You might be
crushing a little.
PATCHI: Whose side
are you on, Alex?
ALEX: My side.
SCOWLER: Admit it.
You're crushing hard.
PATCHI: Nope. Am not.
SCOWLER: Give up! She's
out of your league!
ALEX: But Scowler's heckling was
not Patchi's only problem...
for the north wind had
started to blow...
revealing a musical side effect
to Patchi's perforated head.
(WIND WHISTLING)
What is that noise?
Wait, is that me?
Is my head whistling?
Maybe nobody will notice.
Whoa, what was that?
Ave, ya-ya, please
turn that off.
(CHUCKLES)
Are you okay?
Yeah, just whistling out
of my hole. No biggie.
Told you you'd blow it.
Get it? Blow it.
JUNIPER: Patchi, is that sound
really coming out of your head?
SCOWLER: Uh, yeah it is.
Well, I think it's cool.
You're kidding, right?
No, I'm not.
Hey, I wish my frill
could whistle.
Yeah, I wish my tail rattled.
We could do a duet.
Ow, Scowler!
Butt out, Scowler!
She's my friend.
Shouldn't you ask her
mom for permission?
I don't need to get
permission from her mom!
JUNIPER: Patchi.
Unless, of course, she is
standing right behind me.
Which she is! What
a nice surprise!
Hello, Mrs. Juniper's...
mom. Okay.
- Bye, Patchi.
- Bye-bye, then.
Good to see you.
"Good to see you"? Seriously?
Worst migration, ever.
ALEX: The winter rains
soon descended...
casting a pall over the valley
and all who dwelled within.
The continuous downpour soaked the
ground and dampened spirits...
leaving many in a
very grumpy mood.
(SQUAWKS)
We traveled days on end.
Soon, days turned into weeks,
weeks turned into weekends...
weekends turned
into long weekends.
Well, you get the picture.
By and by, there we were.
Just a few short Miles from
the last mountain pass...
on the way to the
winter grounds.
Many creatures had made
the arduous journey...
not only by land,
but on the wing...
soaring high above the
pastoral terrain.
BOY: Pterosaur, meaning
winged lizard, carnivore.
ALEX: While the poor earthbound
creatures plodded along...
those of us blessed with certain
aerodynamic qualities...
could cover hundreds of
Miles in a single...
Hey, watch it! I have
the right of way here!
(SCREAMS)
You won't get away with this!
You better watch your backs!
I know some very
unsavory people.
Sky hogs!
As I was saying, there it
was, the final mountain pass.
Also known as the Widow-maker,
Dead Man's Canyon, Ambush Alley.
It had a lot of names.
Interesting sidebar for the
scientifically-minded.
Did you know that the Pterosaur
has no natural predators?
PATCHI: Are you
sure about that?
ALEX: Yes, of course. I
don't make this stuff up.
Fascinating
creatures, you know,
light enough to
stay airborne...
yet powerful enough to travel
great distances without rest.
PATCHI: Really? And
no natural predators?
"Alex". Nope. Not even one.
The Pterosaur lives
a charmed life.
Uh-oh.
PATCHI: I think you might have
just jinxed that guy, Alex.
ALEX: Sorry, boss, that's on me!
Keep it real, buddy!
Did I mention that
the Pterosaur
did have one natural
predator...
the Gorgosaurus.
GIRL: Gorgosaurus, meaning
fierce lizard, carnivore.
ALEX: Nicely done. But I think a
little more is needed with this guy.
Allow me to elaborate.
Weighing in at nearly
two and a half tons...
the Gorgosaur measured roughly
26 feet from the
tip of his tail...
to the top of his noggin, and if
you like teeth, he's got teeth.
60 of them, and razor sharp.
Perfect for tearing through
ﬂesh and splintering bones.
His powerful legs propel him
to blazing speeds of up to...
well, no one really knows, but he
certainly was faster than you.
He was equipped
with an uncanny
sense of smell, razor
sharp vision...
and two tiny little arms.
He... (CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry. Seriously, I mean,
what's up with that? I mean...
Okay, sorry, wait. I have
to compose myself. Okay.
The Gorgosaurus had a
large brai... (CHUCKLES)
I'm sorry, I can't
take him seriously
with those tiny
little baby hands.
Look at him, he's so cute.
Okay, I'm sorry, sorry.
But make no mistake, despite his
comically miniature arms... (CHUCKLES)
he was a very good eater...
able to consume hundreds of pounds
of meat in a single feeding.
I'll tell you what, you did not want
to get on a Gorgosaur's bad side.
Oh, no, or on his insides, which
was a distinct possibility.
Especially if you were a big
galumphing double-wide herbivore.
(SNIFFING)
And featured on the menu
on this particular day...
was Pachyrhinosaur Carpaccio
with a garnish of sagebrush...
and just a soupcon
of wild asparagus.
Hey, Pachito! You feel like maybe
getting some exercise today?
- What?
- Just got a strange feeling, that's all.
You might wanna do a
little stretching,
get those hamstrings
nice and loose.
Just in case you decide
to do some cardio.
Why would I be exercising
when I walk 12 hours a day?
Because you might live longer!
Run away!
Run away?! Away from what?! Where
do I go?! It'd be helpful to know!
Keep to the center of the herd,
little bro! Safety in numbers!
What's safe about this?!
I almost got stepped on!
See?!
(SNARLING)
ALEX: The Gorgosaurs enacted their
plan with military precision.
Now these bad boys of
the plains had it down.
They chased and harried their
prey, causing panic...
and introducing mayhem
in their ranks.
PATCHI: You'd freak out too if
they were chasing you, okay?
ALEX: I'm not judging.
Juniper, this way!
Mom, where are you?!
I'm going with Patchi!
PATCHI: Scowler, what are we
doing?! What's happening?!
SCOWLER: Don't worry, as long as we
keep up with the herd, we'll be okay!
ALEX: And here, the nasty
Gorgosaurs separated
the young and the
weak from the herd.
Divide and conquer. Gorgon
practically invented it.
Patchi, what do we do?!
Think happy thoughts!
SCOWLER: Whatever happens,
we have to remain calm!
Remember, they can smell fear!
Sorry, that's not fear.
Juniper, you okay?!
I think I just stepped
in some fear!
They have us cornered!
Truce, truce! Time
out, time out!
PATCHI: Okay, everybody,
I got an idea.
Just back up and
play it very cool.
Like, we don't even
care, look at that
nice stream over there,
let's look at...
Somebody help me!
Juniper! Oh, no!
Swim towards the shore!
I'm trying. I can't swim!
PATCH I: Juniper
needed my help.
With her mom stuck
on the shore,
I suddenly realized
what I had to do.
I had to dive in to save her.
(GRUNTING)
ALEX: You dove in?
PATCHI: That's right.
- That was a dive?
- Yeah, actually.
- It was.
- That was a dive, right there?
Yeah, it was a dive.
Maybe we should
look at that again.
(REWINDING)
(GRUNTING)
Yeah, there you are
with a beautiful dive.
PATCHI: I'll have you know that
was a reverse pike cannonball.
ALEX: I'll give you a 1.5
for degree of difficulty...
and a perfect 10
for imagination.
PATCHI: Help, I can't swim!
ALEX: Hang in there, Patchi!
Whatever you do, try not to drown!
I watched my friend helplessly as he
was swept away into a watery grave.
PATCHI. "Grave"?
I'm still alive.
ALEX: Come on, it's
a figure of speech.
JUNIPER: Help, somebody!
Help!
Oh, thank goodness.
Oh, that was a close one.
Patchi! Over here!
Hang on, Juniper! I'm
coming to save you!
Yeah!
Oh, man! That was close.
I'm exhausted!
SCOWLER: Whoa!
Oh, my gosh!
Whoa, that was scary! Oh, my
gosh, guys, can you help me?
No! Whoa!
PATCHI: Thanks a lot, Scowler!
Nice work!
ALEX: Patchi and the
others were carried off...
by the swift and
treacherous current.
Patchi! Where are you?!
Patchi!
I flew for what
seemed like days...
but I do tend to exaggerate,
so, let's call it 10 minutes.
Then, as I searched for
my dear friend Patchi...
I was confronted by the specter
of his bloated corpse...
cast upon the sand like
a lump of rotting ﬂesh.
- A mere shadow of a...
- Gotcha!
Hey! What gives?
See? I knew you were faking.
That doesn't mean you
can poke my eye out!
Agree to disagree, okay?
(SNEEZES)
Oh, gross!
Mmm. But tasty.
Charge!
Hey, where's Scowler going?
Come on, guys.
Here's the way out!
Oh, wait. Hang on!
Yeah, ocean. I'll
kick your salty butt.
Yup, that's my brother.
(JUNIPER GROANS)
Ouch.
Come on, Juniper. Easy does it.
Juniper! Are you okay?!
Do not peck her eye out.
Okay, relax!
Are you all right? What's
wrong with your leg?
Oh, it's just a scratch.
Mostly I'm starving. I haven't
eaten since yesterday.
Yeah, me neither.
(RUMBLING)
Whoa! Was that your stomach?
Uh, definitely not.
Look!
(ROARING)
What is that?!
(SCOWLER HUMMING)
Smack. What's that?
ALEX: Ah, yes, the
mighty Edmontosaur...
enormous in length,
gargantuan in height...
and his brain? Not so much.
PATCHI: How big is your brain?
ALEX: It's not a competition.
GIRL: Edmontosaurus, meaning
lizard of Edmonton, herbivore.
Whoa.
- Heads up!
- Look out, Patchi!
They look hungry. What
if they want to eat us?
JUNIPER: They don't eat meat,
they eat very large trees.
I'm glad I'm not a tree.
JUNIPER: Patchi. Come on!
ALEX: For once, luck had
smiled on our heroes...
for within those
enormous animals'
minuscule brains was
but one thought:
Food.
PATCHI: What about a beverage?
ALEX: Okay, two thoughts, well,
three, if you want a side dish...
but back to my original point.
It was a most
fortuitous development,
for as the ancient
wisdom tells us:
If you want to know where the
food is, follow the fat guys.
You know what I was thinking?
These guys are probably on their
way to some feeding ground.
Maybe we should follow them.
I just said that!
JUNIPER: Good idea, Patchi.
Thanks.
ALEX: Oh, sure, Patchi,
take all the credit.
Hey! Mind if we join you?
You won't even
know we're here.
In fact, I don't think you
do know we're here. Do you?
No?
Patchi, check it out!
You go left, you go right, you gotta
be smarter than the herd... Ow!
- Move it or lose it, lard butt.
- Ow. Scowler!
Eat my dust.
Again, not a race!
Come on, June. We
gotta keep going.
Hey. Juniper doesn't quit.
I'm going as fast as three
and a half legs can take me.
How's the leg, Juniper?
You need me to carry you?
Nah, you know what? I'm just gonna
park it here for a bit. (SIGHS)
Oh, yeah.
Oh, uh, having a lie-down, yeah.
Sure.
Scowler! Wait up, Scowler!
All right, so I guess we'll
catch up with you...
or something, later?
Guys? (SCOFFS)
Thanks for waiting!
Save us some leafy Greens!
Patchi, you should go on
ahead, I'll catch up.
What are you, crazy? I'm
not going anywhere.
I'm gonna stay with you
until you feel better.
Patchi!
Now where are those laggards?
Ah, I should have guessed.
Hey, I hate to horn in on
your beautiful moment...
but in case you haven't
noticed, it's getting dark.
Juniper, um, we
gotta get going.
Okay, I'll be over here.
I'm sorry to wake you,
but, I don't know...
the tide turned or something.
I don't really know
much about tides.
But the point is, we need
to find another way out.
Okay. Good luck with that.
Okay, yeah, I can
get us out of here.
Time to turn on my
trailblazing skills.
Hey, Patchi, have you ever
had that weird dream...
where a bunch of crabs are
crawling all over you?
No. You know, I've had
the lobster dream but...
Holy crab!
Get them off!
Here they come,
they're swarming
and I don't know if
they're friendly! Ow!
Hey, back off, shoo,
shoo, get out of here!
Oh, I see you like to dance. So,
what will it be, my briny friend?
The mambo?
(VOCALIZING)
The salsa? Perhaps
the deadly lambada?
Tough guy, huh? Well, you've
messed with the wrong...
Ow, ow! Get it off!
(LAUGHS) Look at them wiggle.
Wiggly-wiggly-woo.
That's right, you run away!
You look so stupid!
Oh, boy. Incoming!
What does that mean?
Hey, new friends, where are
you on the food chain?
High, low, middle? Give
us a ballpark... Run!
It's okay, they don't want us!
JUNIPER: Then what
do they want?!
The crabs!
Ew, they just eat them whole?
I guess they're purists.
Come on Juniper, follow me! I'm
pretty sure it's this way.
Lead on, Patchi, but
can we slow it down
a Tad? Still a
little tender here.
Oh, yeah, of course,
no problem.
ALEX: You see, Patchi was
already becoming a leader.
A leader of one, but you
gotta start somewhere.
The sun set for the last time
on the Western horizon...
giving way to sister moon...
who would now hold sway over the
wintery Alaskan wilderness...
piercing the darkness
with her pale blue eyes.
Which simply means,
it'll be dark
in the Arctic for
a very longtime.
PATCHI: (SHIVERS) Yikes!
It's getting kinda chilly.
We should have brought layers.
Are you sure this is the right
way to the feeding grounds?
Of course I'm sure. I got a knack
for these kinds of things.
Besides, I've also got a foolproof
Plan B and his name is Alex.
I hope there's a Plan C,
'cause I'm totally lost.
Did you hear that? We're
lost in this horrible place.
It's just a normal Forest full
of normal foresty things.
What was that?
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMS)
That's not funny!
Take it somewhere
else, furball!
You know, someday these
mammals will go extinct...
and then we'll have the
last laugh. Ha ha!
You know, it isn't actually
that bad out here.
Think about it: A
dark creepy Forest
is really just an open field...
with trees and different
things in it.
You never know what
you're gonna find.
Oops. Watch the log.
Uh, not log, tail.
I hope it's not connected
to this claw in any way.
Or that big toothy muzzle.
Oh, I can't bear to watch...
but I will.
Careful, Patchi, don't
make any sudden movements.
It's another kind of movement
I'm worried about right now.
Okay.
♪  Nice little Gorgo ♪
♪ on the treetop ♪
♪  While I climb over ♪
♪ Please don't wake-up I ♪
Now, I suggest you
slowly and gently...
(SCREAMS)
Run away, run away!
What are you doing? Are you
trying to get us eaten?
No, I'm not trying
to get us eaten.
I'm trying to get
us out of here.
Anyway, he's probably hibernating.
He won't wake-up till spring.
JUNIPER: Maybe we should be a
bit more careful from now on.
Yeah. From now on, I'm gonna be
extra careful and keep it stealthy.
I'm gonna be like a ninja.
There are probably plenty of other
things to worry about in these woods.
Totally.
Like, what other kind of
things you think are out here?
GIRL: Chirostenotes, meaning
narrow-handed omnivore.
- Oh, Don't worry. This is kinda nice, right?
- Mmm-hmm.
Little moonlit stroll.
Sort of like a date.
Well, not like a date.
More like a hangout.
Like a friendly
hang-sesh at night.
(BOTH GASP)
(SCREECHING)
Chirostenotes!
Chiroste-nachos?!
- Notes!
- Whaties?!
Hey, beat it! Note-ies.
Chirostenotes. Enunciate!
PATCHI: What kind
of a name is that?
A long one. Get away!
They give them crazy
names, I would have
called them skinny-neck
pecky thingies.
JUNIPER: That's longer.
Maybe we should just focus.
PATCHI: A little hard to focus
when they keep pecking!
Patchi, they don't
have any teeth!
But I do!
JUNIPER: Yeah!
- Got them good!
- Yeah! That's right!
Who wants to get bit? You?!
Back off, you skinny-neck
pecky thing!
PATCHI: Their
feathers taste gross.
Take a hike, Turkey bird!
Keep it movin'.
What are you looking at?
Better move on!
Yeah, that's what I thought!
(SCREECHING)
And so should we!
(ROARING)
JUNIPER: Wow!
Oh, good, you're
seeing that, too?
Just 'cause I thought it was
that rancid pinecone I ate.
It's so beautiful.
♪  Oh, there's a river ♪
♪ that runs on forever ♪
♪  I'm gonna see where it leads ♪
♪  Oh, there's a mountain ♪
♪ that no man has mounted ♪
♪  I'm gonna stand on the peak ♪
♪  Out there's a land ♪
♪ that time don't command ♪
♪  Wanna be the first to arrive ♪
♪  No time for pondering ♪
♪ why I'm-a wandering ♪
♪  On while we're ♪
♪ both still alive ♪
♪  To the ends of the ♪
♪ earth, would you follow me ♪
♪  There's a world that was ♪
♪ meant for our eyes to see ♪
♪  To the ends of the earth... ♪
JUNIPER: There they are! You
did it! You found them!
We found them.
(CHUCKLES)
Come on! Race you
to the bottom!
JUNIPER: That's my herd!
PATCHI: (LAUGHS)
Slippery!
JUNIPER: Look out below! Whoa!
Wait up!
Somebody got a second wind.
(LAUGHS)
Let's go!
PATCHI: Yeah! Full moon, cool!
JUNIPER: Mom, Dad! We made it!
Hey, everybody, it's us!
- We're back!
- JUNIPER: Incoming!
Hi, Garry. Looking
good, Phyl...
Whoa, Phyllis, watch the tail.
ALEX: Well, well, well, look
who's trotting into camp.
Scowler, back after heroically
abandoning his brother.
Greetings, my fickle friend.
Uh, Alex, bite me.
Mm, don't mind if I do.
(MUNCHING)
Hey! Hey, hey!
Hey, Stretch, get
your own slimy rock.
Yeah.
♪  To the ends of the ♪
♪ earth, would you follow me ♪
♪  There's a world that was ♪
♪ meant for our eyes to see ♪
♪  To the ends of the ♪
♪ earth, would you follow me ♪
♪  If you won't, I must say ♪
♪ my goodbyes to thee I ♪
All right, little swimmy
thingies, I gotcha!
- Aw, man!
- What are you doing?
They've gotta come
up for air sometime.
SCOWLER: Hey, losers!
(CHUCKLES)
They looked. Where you
losers been, huh, Patchi?!
PATCHI: What?! You
left us behind.
- You left me ahead.
- That's ridiculous!
You're ridiculous!
No, you are ridiculous.
Uh-uh, you're ridiculous!
You're ridiculous! (ICE CRACKS)
Oh, so cold!
ALEX: Eventually the
sky, once shrouded
in darkness for
months on end...
was brightened by the
arrival of the sun.
(SQUAWKING)
(SQUAWKS)
(SHRIEKING)
ALEX: The Alphadon came out of
his hole and saw his shadow...
and you know what that
means: Winter was over.
PATCHY. I thought winter was over
if he doesn't see his shadow.
ALEX: You know absolutely
nothing about Alphadon Day.
PATCHI: It was around
that time that I noticed
everybody was going
South again...
but this time in reverse.
ALEX: So North,
in other words.
PATCHY. Exactly.
ALEX: Fortunately, Major was
there to give the word.
(ROARS)
PATCHI: Am I wrong, or was that the
same as the word for going South?
ALEX: It's a very
simple language.
As he began the return
journey to his birthplace...
Patchi reflected on the joys
and heartaches of his
first migration.
JUNIPER: Come on, Patchi.
Northward ho!
SCOWLER: Yeah.
PATCHI: Let's get to the
front, I'm tired of looking
at people's butts
all the time.
ALEX: Marching to a meter set
down by the change of seasons...
Patchi's herd traveled the
same route year after year.
They journeyed South...
then North...
then South again.
I mean, seriously, what's wrong
with West once in a while?
Or East, even, just to
spice things up, you know?
Through it all, his
load was lightened
by the splendid bird that
always had his back.
Patchi and I collected
a lot of memories
on those trips, and
even more bugs.
Gotcha! I'm stuck. I'm stuck.
(GRUNTS)
Don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
No, I love you too. Thanks a lot.
Yeah, I appreciate it, buddy.
But with each passing year
and every migration...
Patchi grew bigger and bigger
and his hole grew
larger and larger.
Hey, I told you one day his hole
would be filled with greatness.
And here I am!
Yes, my little friend Patchi
was not so little anymore.
He had grown into
a young adult...
just in time for the
annual courtship...
when mature males vie for the
affections of the females.
You know something, Patchi?
I love the quality time we
spend together, really.
But isn't it time you declared
your intentions with Juniper?
'Cause headbutting season
has already begun.
(SCOFFS)
I hate headbutting season.
It's like all the adults
suddenly lose their minds.
With all the yelling and the
snorting and the circling...
ALEX: Don't forget
the headbutting.
Yeah, and the headbutting.
It's so... prehistoric.
But it is how things are done.
What? What kind of things?
I cannot interfere with matters of
the heart, it is against my policy!
Patchi loves you.
Huh?
Patchi! I was afraid you
weren't going to show up.
What? Of course I was.
And, wait, what am I showing
up for again? (LAUGHS)
The headbutting
contest, silly.
Major is taking on
all challengers.
Who would be dumb enough to
challenge that guy? He's huge.
(ROARING)
JUNIPER: And it looks
like you're up.
What?!
I should sit this one out, 'cause I
just ate two huge Berry bushes and...
Step aside, Patchi.
(ROARS)
Hey, Major, it's time you went head
to head with a real Pachyrhinosaur!
I'll tell you what: Scowler
does not back down.
What's the big deal?
I could do that!
I've got 50 bugs
on the big guy.
If you're just going to chit
chat, I'm going to get a snack.
Hold my place.
ALEX: Ah, yes, the clash
of the Pachyrhinosaurs.
One of the great spectacles
of prehistoric pugilism. ..
Combining the Grace of ballet
with the stupidity of
banging into things.
This was to be a very
momentous contest...
for it was on that day...
that Scowler not
only took on Major,
the big boss of the
Pachyrhinosaurs...
but he defeated him.
And just like that,
a new Era was born.
(ROARING)
Scowler was the new
leader of the herd.
- Yeah!
- Way to go, Scowler! Nice.
Good fight, Major. Too
bad someone had to lose.
That was you, by the way.
PATCHI: Man, that was epic.
Great job, buddy.
I'm not your buddy, I'm the
leader of the herd now.
Show some respect.
- But-but...
- Patchi!
How was I supposed to know?
Juniper where are you going?
Sorry, Patchi, it's
those stupid rules.
Law of the arctic, little bro.
You snooze, you lose.
But I didn't... I mean...
Hold on. How about a do-over?
Huh? Best of three?
I'm ready now, let's do it!
We're not kids anymore!
Come on, Juniper. Move out!
Oh, and Patchi...
I know, I know, eat your dust.
ALEX: And the herd marched on, but this
time with Scowler leading the way.
SCOWLER: Okay, this
is Scowler's herd...
and things are gonna be different
around here from now on!
Rule number one,
all herd members
will walk a minimum four
feet behind Scowler!
Rule number two, do not speak to
Scowler without first being spoken to.
Rule number three, do not make
direct eye contact with Scowler.
Rule number four, never
question or contradict Scowler.
The first Thursday
of every month
will be known as Scowler
Appreciation Day.
Suggested gifts include,
but are not limited to...
ALEX: As if Patchi's bruised
ego wasn't bad enough...
now he had a big old heap of
heartbreak to go with it.
Hey! Hey, get out,
you lousy squatter.
Cheer up, Patchi, it's not
the end of the world.
That won't come for
another couple years.
PATCHI: Leave me
alone, would you?
ALEX: You wanna talk about it?
You wanna share?
PATCHI: Get off!
ALEX: Okay, you're the boss!
Besides Scowler.
Too soon? Too soon, sorry.
ALEX: The ice and snow had started
to thaw, but Patchi's heart?
Well, that was another matter.
Yep, these were tough times
for our lumbering hero.
But as the saying goes, when life
gives you lemons, make lemonade.
And when life puts
your brother in charge
and takes away the
girl of your dreams...
Well, that's-that's
a tough one.
Let me get back
to you on that.
JUNIPER: Way to go, Scowler. Frozen
water, always fun to walk on.
I wish Juniper would
look back at me,
just give me some
sort of sign.
Hey, I don't remember
coming this way.
Must be one of
Scowler's shortcuts.
Hmm.
Come on, people, try
to keep up here.
Whoa! I heard laughing,
who's laughing?
(ROARS)
(GROANS)
PATCHI: I can't believe we're on a
frozen lake in the middle of spring.
(ICE CRACKING)
Wait a minute. We're on a frozen
lake in the middle of spring?
Juniper!
Tell Scowler it's not safe!
JUNIPER: He won't listen to me.
He won't listen to anybody.
(ROARS)
Juniper, you have to believe me,
we need to get off this ice!
But Scowler's the herd leader. We
have to follow him, it's the rule.
Oh, no!
I told you guys to
pick up the pace!
Come on! No retreating!
ALEX: While Scowler
blundered forward...
Patchi knew he had to move
the herd off the ice.
Everybody, back to shore!
Turn back, everyone.
PATCHI: You guys, it's not safe!
We need to turn back!
Come on, little guy, I got you.
That's it.
PATCHI: Let's go!
Everybody follow me!
Everyone off the ice!
On to shore, everybody!
Just push in!
JUNIPER: Patchi! What now?!
There's too many of us!
Okay. Think! Um...
Knock down the tree and feast
on the leafy Greens up top.
That's it! Follow me!
This way!
(BANGING)
Keep moving!
Push down the trees!
Make a path!
Take that, random tree!
JUNIPER: Whoo-hoo!
Good job, Patchi!
(ROARS)
Hey! He's taking my herd!
Oh, so cold!
ALEX: Patchi's quick thinking had
saved the herd from a frigid fate...
but not everyone was
grateful for his heroics.
SCOWLER: Come on!
Hey, who do you think
you are, huh?!
Boy, looks like Scowler's
pretty mad, huh?
We better just keep moving.
Hey, Patchi!
Look at me! You can't
just take my herd!
That's not the way
things are done!
There's rules, you know!
Come here!
I didn't take them, all right, Scowler?
I had to get them off the ice.
You're welcome to join us!
Oh, don't worry, Patchi...
I will find you
wherever you go!
And then we'll see what's up!
Whatever you say, Scowler.
ALEX: The shadows grew long as the
sun kissed the Western horizon...
casting a ghostly glow over
our fearless protagonist...
and also on Patchi.
I hope Scowler wasn't
serious back there.
He's probably just letting off
steam. He'll get over it.
SCOWLER: Surprise! Ha ha!
So glad you're here,
'cause it's time
to get down to business, Patchi!
Okay. He's not over it.
Just ignore him.
Let's keep going.
You're right, come on.
Hey, Patchi, where you off
to in such a hurry, huh?
(ROARS)
Patchi, don't engage him,
don't take the bait.
What do you want, Scowler?
You stole my herd,
you stole my girl
and now you're
gonna pay for it.
You crossed the line.
You crossed the line when you almost
got everyone killed back there.
Tough talk for a little guy.
Let's see if you can back it up.
(ROARS)
You can have the herd, but
you're not taking Juniper.
You don't have to do this, Patchi,
you don't have to fight him.
(ROARING)
(CHIRPS)
Last chance to walk away!
What's it gonna be?
This ends here!
SCOWLER: Give up!
Yeah, come on!
Oh, you're tougher
than I thought.
You want some more, Patch?
That's what I thought.
And by the way, you're
out of the herd.
Move out!
JUNIPER: Patchi, are
you all right?!
Patchi?
Okay, hang in there, I'm gonna help you.
(GROWLING)
What are you doing, Juniper? I
said move out. You know the rules.
You can't just leave him like
that, he's your brother.
I don't have a brother.
Now get back to the herd!
Juniper, don't go.
ALEX: Well, this is the way
it goes for some of us.
We try our best, we
fight the good fight...
and yet we cannot succeed
against the greater forces.
Aye, poor Patchi.
Lying helpless
with the weight of the
world on his shoulders.
What could bring him back
from the brink of despair?
Well, that's what
friends are for.
Patchi! (TAPPING)
Patchi?
Patchi, come on, you've
got to get up, buddy.
Come on, Patchi, please.
Talk to me.
What is the problem?
Are you hurt?
How about now?
And what about this? Does
that hurt? A little bit?
Uh-oh. Scavengers!
Hey! Get out of here!
Return to your home, nothing
to see here! Go away!
Shoo, shoo!
Patchi, get up!
PATCHI: No.
This is where I belong.
Aw, Alex, what an idiot I was,
trying to be the big man...
thinking I could beat Scowler
and be with Juniper.
No, my friend, you are confusing
ambition with destiny!
Now, I told you when
you were little
that you were going
to be a hero!
And an Alexornis never lies!
Patchi, please, these guys
aren't fooling around, okay?
They're gonna have
a dinner party
and I'm telling you,
you're the main course!
PATCHI: Good.
Shame on you. Imagine what your
father, Bulldust, would say to that.
I don't care.
I have no reason to...
Ouch! Okay, that hurt.
Uh-oh. More customers.
Come on, move it, big guy!
Alex, would you just go away?
I don't want you to see this.
No, Patchi! Don't
let this happen!
Come on! Just get
it over with.
Put me out of my misery.
Ow!
Patchi...
listen to me.
Do not die in vain.
If you're going to die, die for
something like your father did.
He died for you.
But you have someone
to live for.
PATCHI: Juniper.
Juniper!
Getup!
(GROANING)
Get up! Get up, Patchi!
Get it off me!
You are not a piece of meat.
I am not a piece of meat!
Get outta here!
(ROARING)
I'm not afraid of you!
I'm not afraid of anyone!
Wow, that was something! What
did you eat for breakfast?
PATCHI: I ate a bush,
if you must know.
I'm back! Yes!
Look out! Pachyrhinosaur,
on the move!
Yes, Patchi, lumber!
Lumber like the wind!
What are you looking at?
Scram, punks!
Gotta get back,
gotta get back.
Out of my way, skinny-neck pecky things!
(PANTING)
(SCREECHING)
Yeah, right back at you!
Gotta get back,
gotta get back.
ALEX: What Patchi lacked in size,
he made up for in courage.
For nothing would stop him.
Not this time.
I made it.
Juniper!
ALEX: He tracked
along the fringes,
looking for the one who
was once lost to him...
but who now had given him
his new sense of purpose.
Hey, everybody! Has
anyone seen Juniper?
Anyone? Anyone.
Just a quick yes or no.
There she is!
(ROARS)
Juniper!
Juniper! Excuse me!
ALEX: Patchi's hardships
were swept away
by the vision of
his true love.
His heart Sang and his spirit
soared, and at that moment...
he would have walked through
a thousand dinosaur butts...
or even a million, if only to
get to his beloved Juniper.
Patchi, you're okay!
I was afraid I was never
going to see you again.
Don't worry, you'll be
seeing plenty more of me,
because there's something
I want to tell you.
- Really?
- I'm just gonna say it.
Go on.
Because this is
the right moment.
- Say it!
- Juniper...
(ROARING)
Huh?
What is it? Wait,
what's going on?
What's all the panic?
ALEX: Patchi would soon
realize that the herd
had entered an all-too-familiar
mountain pass.
Wait, I know this place.
Ambush Alley.
ALEX: Ambush alley, Dead Man's
Canyon, Scowler's Folly.
That's a new name, by the way.
And you'll know why in a minute.
Patchi, the Gorges! We've
gotta get out of here, now!
(GRUNTING)
PATCHI: Scowler?
Scowler!
Patchi, don't just stand there!
Get out of here! Run!
But you're my brother! We
have to stick together!
(ROARS)
I meant, run away!
I know what you meant.
Go on! Don't worry,
I'm wearing them out!
I'm not going anywhere!
Patchi, save the herd!
Lead them to safety!
You don't owe me anything,
little bro! Don't be a hero!
What do I do? What do I do?
Hang on, you guys!
I'm going to give you some air
support! Everybody look to the skies!
Help is on the way!
Hold on. Bug break.
An army marches on it's
stomach, you know.
You know I'm right, Patchi.
I'm already a goner.
Take the herd away from here!
Go while you still can!
ALEX: Patchi.
Do not die in vain.
If you are going to die,
die for something
like your father did.
He died for you.
(ROARS)
That's right, I'm talking
to you, tiny arms.
Everyone, follow me!
Come on!
(GROANING)
You messed with the
wrong herd, lizard boy!
You're about to get served!
Told you!
ALEX: Both sides
battled ferociously...
but the Pachyrhinosaurs had one
thing the Gorgosaurs did not:
A former runt with a
hole in his head...
and a lion in his heart.
But even the greatest
of heroes...
can sometimes benefit
from a lucky break.
(SNAPS)
(SCREECHING)
That one's for my brother!
And that one's for my dad!
And this one...
That's so you'll remember me!
That's right, you heard me.
Get out of here!
Name's Patchi! And I'll
see you next winter!
(ROARING)
I don't believe it.
Patchi did it!
I was distracted. What happened?
Did we win'?
What happened? Payback.
That's what happened.
ALEX: I'm telling you, you
can't make this stuff up.
After everything
he'd been through,
Patchi's moment had
finally arrived.
He was the undisputed
leader of the herd...
and nobody was
prouder than me.
You hurt, Scowler?
I'm okay. Thanks.
You know, Patch, you didn't
have to do that after...
you know, what I did to you.
So I just wanted to say...
(ROARS LOUDLY)
I deserve that.
Guess this means you're the
leader of the herd now.
So, you might as well
go ahead and say it.
Really? Okay.
Well, let's move 'em out!
SCOWLER: Sounds good.
PATCHI: Yeah, that
felt pretty good.
Hey, Patchi, you were
pretty great out there.
Yeah, you too. Remind me
never to headbutt with you.
Juniper, listen, it's time
to talk about the future.
You mean the Cenozoic Era?
No, I mean the Patchi
and Juniper Era.
Oh, I think I'm gonna
like the future.
ALEX: With the
herd at his heels,
Patchi walked across the
grasslands of Alaska...
and into the future.
Which, as always, was
full of surprises.
PATCHI: Excuse me?!
Hi, there. Can I help
you find something?
No'? You sure?
Okay, then get out!
(SHRIEKS)
Go back to Turkey
town and stay out!
Patchi, are you messing
with the Troodons again?
I thought I asked you
to watch the eggs.
I am watching them, but they
keep not doing anything.
I told you, it takes time.
You have to be patient.
PATCHI: I know, but we're
talking about our whole future.
Why does the future always
take so long to get here?
JUNIPER: Shh! You hear that?
It's time, Patchi. This is it!
I don't believe it.
Wow, look at that!
Oh, he's beautiful.
He looks just
like his old man.
Well, if he's anything like
you, we'll have our hands full.
Well, look what we have here.
Allow me to congratulate you
on this happiest of occasions.
As far as names go,
may I suggest Alex?
It means, "Ridiculously
handsome bird."
And as for you, baby
Alex, how about a kiss?
Okay, bye-bye.
♪  Live like a warrior ♪
♪  Today, today, ♪
♪ live like you wanna ♪
♪  Let yesterday burn ♪
♪ and throw it in a fire ♪
♪  In a fire In a fire ♪
ALEX: Patchi's story may have faded
into the mosaic of history...
but evidence of the day
that a Gorgosaur's mouth...
ran into a Pachyrhinosaur's
head still exists.
And what happened after that,
well, that's hard to say.
It's a question
that has intrigued
dinosaur lovers
for generations.
I'll only say that sometimes, you
have to dig for the answers.
A Gorgosaur's?
Looks to be.
Uncle Zack?
Hey, Ricky.
Come see what we found.
Uncle Zack...
look, the tooth!
Ricky, did you bring it?
Here it is.
- RICKY: Cool!
- UNCLE ZACK: Wow!
That's it, it fits!
I knew it'd be worth coming back!
(SQUAWKING)
ALEX: Kid, What
did I tell you?
Every fossil tells a story!
Hey, come and see me
in a museum sometime.
I got my own diorama
and a tiki bar!
As for the rest of you,
this is the end of my tail.
No, literally, you see it? No,
really, honestly, it's the end.
That's it. We're done.
Fade to black.
(GROWLING)
(ROARS)
ALEX: Oops, forgot about that part.
(CHUCKLES)
Gotcha!
♪  Today, today, ♪
♪ live like you wanna ♪
♪  Let yesterday burn ♪
♪ and throw it in a fire ♪
♪  In a fire In a fire ♪
♪  Fight like a Warrior ♪
♪  Today, today, ♪
♪ live like you wanna ♪
♪  Let yesterday burn ♪
♪ and throw it in a fire ♪
♪  In a fire In a fire ♪
♪  Live like a warrior ♪
♪  Feel like the world ♪
♪ don't love you ♪
♪  They only want ♪
♪ to push you away ♪
♪  Some days people ♪
♪ don't see you ♪
♪  You feel like ♪
♪ you're in the way ♪
♪  Today you feel, as ♪
♪ if everyone hates ♪
♪  Pointing their fingers ♪
♪ Looking at your mistakes ♪
♪  You do good, they want great ♪
♪  No matter what you give ♪
♪ they still want to take ♪
♪  Give your love and ♪
♪ they throw it back ♪
♪  You give your heart ♪
♪ they go on attack ♪
♪  When there's ♪
♪ nothing left for you ♪
♪  Only thing that ♪
♪ you can do, say ♪
♪  Today, today, ♪
♪ live like you wanna ♪
♪  Let yesterday burn ♪
♪ and throw it in a fire ♪
♪  In a fire In a fire ♪
♪  Fight like a warrior ♪
♪  Today, today, ♪
♪ live like you wanna ♪
♪  Let yesterday burn ♪
♪ and throw it in a fire ♪
♪  In a fire In a fire ♪
♪  Live like a warrior I ♪
http://subscene.com/u/659433
Improved by: @Ivandrofly